and the video we have discussed about the TCP and UDP, how the protocol will be working, and why it's a connection lesson, connection oriented. So we will discuss one more thing that will be added in the transport layer. So that was a port number, many of them know what's port number. So let's start the discussion about the port number. Okay. So in computers, there are a lot of other things that we have to do with the system. So we have to do with the system.
And in computers, there are many sovies of air running. You are using the Google Chrome for reaching out to Google or any other public service you need, or you need to transfer some files to one place to another so we are using FTP for file transfer protocol.
And there is a DNS or sending domain name system. There is a lot of ports and protocols will be running in your machine. Maybe there's SQL sovies. So SQL will use some other ports.
So why we need this port for in OSL air in transport, why this port number is added in the transport layer. Let's discuss that. Okay. So in the computer, so let's take this computer as an example. So in this computer, there's an application called Chrome or running. Okay. And there is one more application was running like zoom.
And again, there is another application like MySQL. This service was running. Okay. So this computer was sending some data to multiple servers. This server is for a Chrome and another server is for a zoom and another server for my SQL.
So this is for the MySQL and it's for a zoom and it's for a Google. So it was using different servers and different application to reach out to that server side.
So if there is no port numbers where specified your computers don't know which data will be sent to which application. Maybe if there is no port numbers. So this zoom will send the data to this Chrome.
So the packet will be it will be confused before arriving into the machine. So we are using the specific port numbers for that in the state. Yes, we know when we searching in the Google, there is one of the protocols that added like it's a HTTP. So we have a separate port number for HTTP.
Yes, it's a 443 that will be added. That will be added in our in the transport layer. Okay. So the TCP or UDP that will be added and the specific port number that will be added in our data. Okay.
In the transport layer. So the data knows which servers I need to reach and which applications I need to reach out to the results. Okay.
So for example, the Chrome was running on now 443. So this port number, the Chrome was using and it was accusing something to Google by using the port number 443. So now the Google servers know which application which port numbers I need to send. So it will directly send the data to the chrome.exe.
Okay. And there assume application may be a zoom or sending an in a three zero five zero port. So it will send this similar result video streaming to the particular zoom application and the MySQL was running as a three zero.
Ignance for an example. So the MySQL know which which service which service I need to send. Okay. By using the port, it will track which application I need to send the data. Okay. We are using port number for that if there is a no port number. So we are unable to track the data. So where it will be where it will be arrived. It will be arrived in zoom or it will be arrived in my SQL application.
So we have a several protocols for that. Okay. If we are using the FTP, if you want to transfer file from one place to another. So we are using the FTP protocol and SSH for our configurations. So we can briefly see what what are the common ports and common ports and protocols in the upcoming videos.
But now we can understand what support okay because the port will put numbers will be added in the transport layer. Right. So this is the explanation for the port. Why the port numbers will be added in our data packets. Okay. So I think you enjoyed the video and I hope you can you have cleared.
You have a clear understanding about the port number. So let's end this video and we will continue in the next video. We will continue in the next layer called a network layer. Bye bye.